吃吧, 为什么不吃？
Eat Why don't you eat 7
就算你抓我, 又能领到多少奖金呢？
Not much reward even if you arrest me
不如放了我, 我给你双倍奖金
Let me go and I'll reward you double
好, 等你投胎做了好人再说吧
Okay. when you turn over a new leaf
用不着得意 ， 奖金你不一定拿得到的
Don't delight. you can't get the reward
真的？
Is it true'?
我已告诉你,我兄弟很厉害的,放了我吧!
My men are terrific Let me go
放你的屁
Let you go ! Bloody nonsense
连你帽子都不认得,不知道认你的样子又怎样？
It's possible you'll go unidentified
不要开枪, 我是猛丁哥
Don't shoot. I'm Mandingo
不要开枪, 是大哥的
Don't shoot. it's big brother
小心枪失火
Don't misfire
叫他们全部出来, 装得像样一点 ， 来
Tell them all to come out and behave I'm okay:
I've fixed him
死不了, 我搞定了他
I'm okay. I've fixed him
出来, 快点出来
Come out. come out quick
好, 我们迎接大哥
Good. let's welcome brother
大哥没义气, 出卖了我们
Big brother's unfriendly. he's betrayed us
不必多管了, 我们走
Never mind. let's go
你是我的钱, 这样就想走？
Don't go away. you're my windfall
现在告诉我, 奖金我拿不拿到？
Tell me can I get the reward?'
可以, 陈查礼一定拿得到的
Yes
早点说就不用被打了
Why didn't you say so earlier'?
威士忌梳打
Whisky Soda
不用找了!... 谢谢
Keep the change
谢谢!
Thank you
今天的牌真邪
Today's hand is eerie
对不起
Sorry
三张A, 我拿主意
3 aces my say
三张二都出现了,难道底牌还有一张二？
3 deuces already A fourth deuce. no way'
全部押下去
Bet everything
谢谢!
Thank you
不用!
Don't mention it
有话留待扫墓再说, 跟不跟呀？
Are you going to follow'?
开给我看
Show me
三夫劳对三张A, 赢定了
Full House vs 3 aces. You'll win for sure
你怎么知道？
Are you sure'?
你会打没把握的仗吗？
You never fight any battle with out confidence
三夫劳？
Full House'?
有什么理由四张二同时出现的？
How come all 4 deuces appear together'?
就是这样巧合的
Just a coincidence
碰着这种冤家牌, 输得口服心服了吧!
Do you concede defeat now?'
等一等, 出老千还想收钱
Wait. you've rigged it!
只是输钱吧! 小心连性命也输掉!
It's only money. don't lose your life
还不快道歉!
Go and say Sorry'
神经病, 你说道歉就要道歉的吗？你是谁呀？
Nuts' Who are you'?
他就是猎犬陈查礼
He's Hound Charlie Chan
不认识我不要紧
You don! have to know me
最要紧是认识他, 快枪马云龙
But you must know mm Sharpshooter Ma Yun-lung
比你捉贼拿奖金容易吧
It's easier than getting a reward
你也不是每次这么幸运的
You're not always so lucky
快枪有什么用, 最要紧是真枪
H's a real gun that counts not fast draw
你来干什么？
What are you doing'?
为了一点私事
Some personal matter
怎样吗?...又为了钱？
Money again')
陈先生
Mr Chan
陈先生, 对不起, 我来迟了
Mr Chan sorry Fm late
不要紧
Never mind
原来是为了红颜知己
So you're doing it for a girlfriend
人生在世, 难得有个好知己
Fiends are hard to come by
他是谁？
Who is it'?
一个为爱疯狂的人
He's madly in love
我干爹呢？
Where's my godfather'?
老爷他…
He
你先出去
Go out first
保什么呀？我看保险公司也保不住了
Even the insurance Co may be lost
我真糊涂, 为了贪宋金荣的保险费
For the sake of the big premium
我竟然答应了他去承保那本可兰经
We agreed to unsure the Koran
我太贪心了, 万一出了错
I'm greedy If anything goes wrong
那可怎么办？
What than?
难道要把整间保险公司赔给别人？
You'll lose the Insurance Co'?
是的, 完了, 我完了
I'm all finished
我抚养了你这么多年, 现在只有全靠你了!
You were my charge now my succor
干爹, 你放心
Don't you every worry
没人可以偷吴氏公司所承保任何物件
No one can lift a Ng-insured hair
老板, 今晚有很多三山五岳的人混了进来
Boss. many underworld people are here
还不替我盯着?...是!
Keep a Watch for me
方秘书, 他来了 ？
Secretary Fang. is he coming?
不是, 是市长来了, 要我替你招呼他吗?
No. it's the mayor. Shall I greet him?
叫他自便好了
Tell him to help himself
老板, 还没有动静
Boss. still no development
叫我拿这本经书出来, 自己这么晚还不来
Here's the Koran. But where's he'?
有事发生怎么办呢？
What if anything happens'?
他叫你拿出来当然是有原因的
He must have his reason for that
宋老板, 你不用紧张
Boss Sung. don't be nervous
我出去看看他来了没有? 去吧!
Let me see if he's coming
欢迎
Welcome
阿龙, 那本经书我一定要偷到手
I must get the Koran
为了我这未来的老婆, 拼了性命我也要拿到
For my future wife.
I must get it evenly risking my life
这本可兰经不知道值多少钱？
l-low much is it worth?
是无价之宝
Priceless
真没想到我家牺牲这么大就是为了这本经书!
Just think we fight for the Koran
我一定要得到手
I'll get it by all means
我看不简单, 神探也来了
The detective-S here too
不一定要你讲, 你可以不讲
You may choose not to speak
快点说!
Speak up
一句就够了, 洗手间在那边
The toilet is over there
请! 谢谢!
Thank you
吴大小姐, 为什么这么晚？
Miss Ng. why are you so late'?
这位一定是陈先生了
He must be Mr Chan
对, 你好!... 你好!
l-low do you do? I-low do you do'?
令尊呢？
Where's your father'?
家父正在安排保护经书的事
Daddy's arranging to protect the Koran
那就要费心一点了
It requires meticulous planning
明天你们保险公司就要负责保护经书
Tomorrow you'll be responsible for its safety
不然出错的话, 麻烦就大了
If anything goes wrong. big trouble
明天开始我会帮吴老板负责保护经书
Tomorrow I'll help protect the Koran
太好了, 两位请随便...
Good. please
好, 谢谢!
Thanks
弄出这种场面, 分明是存心不良
The way they wok
they must be up to something
他们想把你的保险公司吞掉
They Want to swallow up your company
马云龙, 你对这本经书也感兴趣吗？
Yun-lung. are you interested in the Koran too?
你不是说过你不是为公事而来的吗？
You said you were not conning on business?
对不起, 由明天起, 我承担了这本经书的保险
Sorry. I'll insure it as of tomorrow
你是说如果我们还继续是朋友的话,就要今晚偷？
You mean I have to steal it tonight'?
什么事？
What happened'?
干什么…
What are you doing'?
有没有人失去了钱包？
Anyone Mast a purse?
钱包…
Purse'?
我遗失了…
I did
你呢？
Any you'?
我失去了银包
We lost my purse
全部在地上了
They're all on the floor
不用这么隆重跪下来迎接我了
No need to Welcome me on your Knees
起来…
Arise. arise
老狐狸卓非凡？
Old Fox Cho Pei-fan?
看来想拿经书的不止我们两人
It seems we are not alone
爸爸
Daddy
卓老, 为什么这么晚？
Cho Why are you so late?'
不晚, 现在正是时候
It's now the right time
有本领的就是有本领
You really are expert
有本领的不止是我一个呀!
I'm not the only expert
宋老板, 为什么会这样子的？
Boss Sung. Why?
没事, 只是玩玩而已
It's all right. only for fun
想不到每件事都夸自己很快的快枪马云龙
I never imagined Sharpshooter Ma Yum-lung
真的来得这么快
could be that fast
快才不会吃亏
I shan't stand to lose then
卓老, 没见你这么久, 看来越来越高
Cho. you're getting taller
这位一定是一出道, 就令人闻名丧胆的猎犬陈查礼了!
You must be that outstanding
Hound Charlie Chan
前辈过奖了, 只是长江后浪推前浪
Thank you Newcomers beat the old
一代新人葬旧人
like the waves overtaking each other
我们后辈是不想的
We youngsters won't like to see that
想也没用的, 你没听说过姜是越老越辣的吗？
Hopeless. I-lave you heard the older.
the more sophisticated'?
对, 人老了没这么容易找饭吃
Well. life is hard for an old man
利用那本经书去赚些钱吧!
Earn some money on the Koran
我卓非凡靠的是真材实料,赚的是真金白银
I'm worth my weight in gold
不像有些人为了女人做一些无聊的事
I don't do silly things
for women like some do
老狐狸你…
Old Fox
两位就当是给我面子, 别插手这件事
Please stay out of this for my sake
我只是希望物归原主
I only hope the real owner will get it back
要放手的应该是你们两人
You two should give up
能够和两位交手, 简直是平生快事
It's my pleasure to fight with you
只有可能失手, 绝对不可能放手的
I may slip but I never give up
宁失信于天下, 莫失信于红颜
Better alienate the world than a woman
我是不会临阵退缩的
I won't back out at the last minute
原来两位都很希望得到那本经书
So you both want to get the Koran
不过我认为要看看自己够不够斤两
But you must gauge your ability
秤一秤就知道了
A test WM show n
随时奉陪
Welcome
你们不是想在大庭广众面前玩吧？
Are you going to play in public?
不如我们到偏厅玩吧!
Let's go to the living room
好, 没问题!
No problem
这副牌两位没问题吧!
Is this poker okay to you'?
没有
Yes
赌钱我想大家也没有兴趣
Gambling may not interest you
不如赌一条路, 输了就要让路
Let's play straight. Losers must give up
怎样赌呀？
HOW?
除了十点半, 什么也可以
Anything except 10 1/2
爽快, 我们就赌唆哈, 一次过派五张
Good let's play stud poker 5 cards at once
你的意思是跑马仔
You mean m one go
好, 一局定输赢
OK. one game decides it
你们两位都是江湖上的高手
You're both experts
在牌上找几张A给自己, 实在太容易了,对吗？
It's easy to get aces. isn't it?
不如掉转来玩,拿着输的牌当赢,好吗？
L-low about reversing the rankings?
好, 斗小吧!
Okay. the smaller card wins
没问题!
No problem
为了避免出老千, 由你的顽皮妹派牌!
To avoid rigging. let your daughter deal
不行, 规则由我定,又由我的女儿派牌, 不公平的!
No. it's not fair to let my daughter deal
不如由马少的红颜知己派牌
Let master Mas gm do n
我不会的
I can't
那正好啊!
So much the better
等一等!
Wan
从底抽上三张
Take 3 cards from the bottom
可以派了
Deal now
等一等, 下两张
Wan put two on the bottom
你呢？
What about you?'
继续派!
Deal as usual
二 、 三 、 四 、 五 、 七
我也是, 如果是斗花, 你连这张七也输掉!
Me too For flushes you lose on the'?
斗什么七？什么七也要输给我
You Muse an any 7
现在是斗小, 你以为斗大吗？
Now we're playing reverse values
对, 你说有什么牌比不是牌更小呢?
Right. any card is smaller than nothing'?
有两张废牌走出来, 应该不算的
The two Discards should not be counted
我们有言在先, 一局定输赢
We agreed that one game will decide
斗大, 我三张A最大
In big. our 3 aces are the biggest
斗小,我有一对废牌,牌不成牌, 一定输的!
In small. a pair of discards do me in
谢谢两位承让
Thank you for conceding
老狐狸, 既然你蛮不讲理,我也不客气了!
Old Fox. I'll be nasty too
我跟你干脆的再赌一手!
Let's have one final bet
不用怕!
Don't worry
查礼, 你认为怎么样？
Charlie. what do you say'?
他说跟你赌, 没有说要跟我赌
He wanted to bet with you not me
好, 我替我爸爸跟你赌
Okay. I'll bet with you for my daddy
老狐狸, 拿女儿的性命作赌注, 太大了吧!
Old fox. isn't your daughter's
life a big stake'?
我们走江湖的人性命是很贱的
Lives of the underworld are cheap
而且我不相信你拔枪比子弹快
I don't think you can draw faster than bullets
如果这支枪没有子弹…
If this gun has no bullets
堂堂快枪手, 枪会没有子弹？
A sharpshooter has an unloaded gun?
你赌扑克也有废牌
You had two discards in poker
算我们打成平手了
We're getter even
以后各走各路
Let's each go our own Way from now on
谢谢卓老给我一条路
Thank you Cho
别走
Hold it
我也要跟你赌一手,看看我有没有性命保护这本经书
My bet is I'll live to protect the Koran
到你了
You turn
卓老, 是不是好久没出来走江湖, 生命矜贵了吗？
Your life's getting precious now. Che'?
卓老, 为什么找这些来玩吗？
Cho Why play this?
输了连性命也没有了
You may even lose your life
不一定, 如果查礼肯放弃保护经书,就能保着性命!
Not if Charlie gives up
protecting the Koran
经书我一定要保护的
I'll protect it for sure
我连续开了两枪, 轮到你开两枪了
I fired 2 shots successively.
现在轮到你了
it's your turn
今晚我替陈先生作主, 不再继续玩了
I'll decide for Mr Chan. It's over now
是不是的, 陈先生？
Is that right. Mr Chan?
随便!...
Okay
宋老板…
Boss Sung
就当给我面子吧!
Please give me some face
好, 就当给你面子
Okay
我们有机会再玩好了
Let's play again next time
各位请便
Please
了不起, 陈查礼, 拿我的枪来吓唬老狐狸!
Charlie. you did
well to scare Old Fox with my gun
都是学你以胆博胆而已
It was bluff I learned from you
祝你好运
Good luck
陈大哥, 他们分明是要抢走那本经书
They were obviously after the Koran
竟然会遇到他们, 这次麻烦了
Having come on them. we're in trouble
走吧!
Let's go'
阿龙, 这本可兰经对我实在太重要了
The Koran is vital to me
爷爷为了偷这本经书, 死得不明不白
My grandfather got killed for it
我爸爸为了它也变得疯疯癫癫
My grandfather became a lunatic for it
如今有了这经书的下落我一定要偷到手
So I must get it
无论如何你也要帮我的忙
You must hem me
为了要娶你, 我不惜任何代价
I'll do anything to marry you
你的事就是我的事
Your business is my business
我一定会帮你把可兰经拿回来
I surely shall help you get It
各位, 我虽然不是吴氏保险公司的人
Although I'm not with the insurance company
但是为了报答干爹对我的养育之恩
I must pay back my debt
这件事我一定负责到底
I shall continue to be responsible
查礼, 时间差不多了
Charlie. the time's almost up
我知道
I Know
今天早上我看过地形, 查过路线
I checked the location and
the route this morning
我们可以分六条路运经书到展览馆
We can send the Koran by 6 routes
所以你们要分为五组
You must be divided into 5 teams
如果我没估计错误的话
If I'm not mistaken
宋金荣一定会派人在半路截劫
Sung will send men to intercept en route
我们要誓死保经
We mush risk our lives to protect it
好, 出发... 是
Okay. let's start
你跟我一组
You belong to my team
是!
Yes
这里有五张路线图交给你保管
Keep these 5 route maps in custody
是!
Yes
小明, 小心一点呀!
Ming. be alert
是!
Yes
不要弄丢了呀!
Don't lose it
知道了, 爸爸
Yes daddy
我们三代都在这里工作的
The 4 generations of us all work here
我知道!
I Know
查礼
Charlie
一切拜托
I'll count on you
谢谢陈大哥
Thank you brother Chan
全交给你了
I'll count on you
不用
No need
陈先生, 太夸张了点吧
Mr Chan. that's too ostentatious
你说我的可兰经该放在哪个箱子好呢？
Which box shall I put the Koran in?
能不能借这房间一用？
Can we use this room?
行, 没问题!
No problem
方秘书, 给他... 好!
Secretary Fang. give it to him
谢谢!
Thank you
陈先生, 由现在开始, 你要承担这本可兰经的保险
Mr Chan as of now you'll unsure the Koran
只是展览期内, 你应付得了的, 陈先生
Can you hahdle the exhibition period?
走吧!
Let's go
小明!
Ming
陈大哥!
Brother Chan
请你叫兄弟们进来... 是
Please bring the men here
兄弟们来了
They're here
上锁, 烧火漆
Lock it. wax-seal it
小明, 把路线图交给他们...是
Ming. give the route maps to them
如果你们中途被人截劫的话, 就把空箱交给他们好了
If you should be intercepted on the way
无谓为了个空箱去跟人家拼命
Let them take away the empty boxes
空箱？
Empty boxes?
可兰经由我随身携带
I'm keeping the Koran myself
明白的话就出发...是
If everything's clear. we'll start
陈大哥, 我们出发了... 好
Brother Chan. let's start
陈查礼, 你真行!
Charlie Chan. you're fantastic'
用五个箱 、 五架车运一本经书, 真棒!
5 trucks and 5 boxes to ship one book
想转移我的目标？没这么容易
You can't divert my attention
经书一定在他身上
He must be keeping it with him
找两个人弄妥他... 是
Get tow men to fix him
没用的, 任何事情要靠抢的话
No way. If violence works.
you don't need me
就用不着请我来了, 用点脑吧!
Use your head
陈大哥, 兵分五路行不行的？
Can we move in 5 different routes?
不知道
I don't know
我们会不会有危险的？
Would we be in danger?
不知道
No idea
什么也不知道？
Why?
我们现在去哪里？
Where are we going'?
好热, 先去洗个澡
It's hot. let's take a bath first
洗澡？
Bath?
两位老板, 对不起!
Sorry bosses
你们来迟了, 刚好客满
You're late. we're full
过来休息一下吧!
Come and take a rest
先生, 已经说过没有位子了
I already said it's full. sir
不要吵!
Quiet
睡觉吧!
Go to bed
陈大哥, 这么紧张的情况之下, 你真的还去洗澡？
How can you take a bath now?
洗澡可以松驰神经, 千万不要太紧张
Bath can relax. Don't be nervous
一齐来洗澡吧!
Let's take a bath together
不要了, 保护经书要紧
No. it's important to protect the Koran
你的经书放在哪里？
Where have you put the Koran?
我已告诉你是随身携带的
I'm keeping it with me. as I told you
我出去看守着 ， 你快一点
I'm going out to have a look. Hurry up
厉害呀!
Great
陈大哥!
Brother Chan
干什么？没有看过吗？
What are you doing? Haven't
you seen it before?
不是, 经书呢？
Where's the Koran?
应该在展览馆
Should be in the Exhibition Hall
究竟去了哪里？还没回来
Where're they? Still not back?
为什么这么晚呢？
Why so late?
你认为陈查礼有没有问题呀？
Anything wrong with Charlie Chan?
我不管他有没有问题, 我最担心我的儿子有没有问题
Fm only wormed about my son not mm
王管家
Butler Wong
你放心, 你的儿子没事, 还很聪明呢!
Don't worry . Your son's fine & smart
爸爸
Daddy
阿明, 你没事吧？
Ming. are you all right'?
没事, 我们被人中途拦劫, 我差点不能回来见你了
Yes, we were intercepted
and nearly failed to retune
怎么样？
How then?
贼人很厉害, 一拳可以把墙壁打倒
The thug punched that wall down
我是问可兰经怎么样？
I mean the Koran
经书在其中一个箱子里
It's in one of the boxes
又是空的, 在哪个箱里？
Empty too. Which box?
幸亏在这里
Luckily it's here
死人塌楼也不要紧, 最要紧是这本经书不要失落
Come What may We must protect the Koran
你不要怪我们老爷, 他不是不关心人命!
Don't blame our master
傻瓜, 我不会怪他的
Idiot. I won't blame him
吃我们这口饭不需要别人关心
People in our line need our care
最要紧自己小心
All We need ls to be men
好像我们刚才这样子？
The way we were just new?
现在才是刚开始
It's now only the beglnmng
对…
Right, right
先生, 这是什么东西？
What's this, sir?
对不起
Sorry
小姐
Miss
对不起, 不要走太近, 请过去那边
Sorry keep away go over there
小姐, 什么事？
What happened. Miss?
小心…
Careful
小姐, 你没事吧？
Miss. are you all right'?
你也是的, 不要让孕妇进来嘛!
You shouldn't have admitted a pregnant woman
你没有说过, 陈先生又不在, 现在怎么办呀?
What now? Mr Chan's not here
大家帮忙先送她到医院去吧!
Let's help take her to a hospital
不要乱来,千万不要碰她...你是谁？
Don't touch her. don't do anything foolish
Who are you?
医生？
A doctor?
请大家站开一点, 不要站得太近
Please keep away
谢谢…
Thank you
来不及送她到医院去了,我要立刻替她接生
Too late. I must deliver for her
在这里接生？
Here?
快点立刻替我准备
Prepare everything for me new
准备什么？
What?
尽快疏散人群
Disperse the crowd at once
疏散人群?
Break off the crowd
快点!... 对不起…
Hurry up
还不快点拿屏风挡着？
Get the screen at once
拿屏风来…, 这儿…
Show me the screen
医生, 你有什么需要就吩咐我们吧!
Doc. tell us if you need anything
行了, 我知道
Okay. I will
出去吧…
Go out
继续叫
Keep screaming
让一让…
Excuse me
病人在哪里？
Where's the patient
在下面, 我带你们去
Down below. I'll take you here
医生, 救护人员来了
Doc. the rescue worker's are here
我现在没事了
I'm all right
误会了 ， 还不能生下来
Only a mistake She can't deliver now
陈大哥 ， 正想找你
I was looking for you . brother Chan
刚才有个孕妇差点在里面生孩子
Just now a pregnant woman
nearly gave birth here
我知道, 她不是生孩子, 是来偷经书的!
I Know she came to steal the Koran
偷经书？
The Koran?
不用怕, 就算我肯, 也有人不肯呀!
Don't worry. it's okay
你替我调查马云龙, 看看他在哪里?
Check where Yun-lung is
你去跟踪卓非凡...,  是
Go and follow Cho Fei-fan
如果有事发生的话, 去酒吧找我吧!
If anything happens. find me at the Bar
我先去调查一下,...小心点
I'll go and check
你猜我会不会打中呢？
Guess if I'll hit it?
照刚才这样, 这竿一定是黑球了
Must be the black ball this time
老板
Boss
这次糟了, 大小不良失败了
Bad they've flopped
为什么不早一点告诉我？
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
第七张了
The 7th
快点…
Hurry up
胜败乃兵家常事
Win or lose counts for nothing
输什么都没问题, 千万不要输心情
Don't ever get discouraged
你心情很好吗？
Are in a good mood?'
我当然是心情好
Surely I am
老板, 桌子弄好了, 球已放在原位了
Boss, the table's ready
the balls in position
现在机会在手中
Now the chance ls in my hands
跟着黑球在袋口
Follow that black ball in the pocket
心里充满无限的信心
I'm full of confidence
爸爸, 已经给了他电话, 他说一切搞定了!
Daddy. I called him and he said OK
你还有带了其他人来的吗？
Have you brought other men?
宋老板除了找我之外
Apart from hiring me. Boss Sung also
也有另外找人中途拦劫, 对吗？
got others to rob. is that right?
我不把所有的鸡蛋放在同一个篮子里
Don't put all eggs in one basket
是我做生意的第一个原则
is our business motto
不把所有拍档带在身边,是我们走江湖的不二法T!
Don't bring all men along
is our underworld rule
宋老板, 你就算不把鸡蛋放在篮子里
Boss, Sung. you shouldn't have put
也不要随处乱放呀!
the eggs in wrong maces too
不然很容易被踩破的
Otherwise they may break
女儿, 我们走
Darling. let's go
卓老, 你们去哪里？
Cho. where are you going?
让人家跟踪
To be followed
让人家跟踪？
To be followed?
又在你们的前面
I'm in front of you
爸爸, 为什么没有人跟踪我们的？
Daddy. why is no one following us?
跟踪的人不一定在后面的, 傻女
They may not be behind us. silly girl
年轻人
Young man
为什么一路跟着我们？
Why have you been following us?
呀, 为什么要跟着你们, 你们弄错了!
Why have I been following you?
我闪!
I'll duck
不要过来呀!...去死!
Keep away
小妞, 不要再逼我出手了!
Miss. don't force me to use violence
来吧!
Come on
怕不怕？
Are you afraid?
年轻人, 出来做世界要看清楚对象才行呀!
Young man. you've picked
on the wrong objective
对, 小弟该死, 不自量力, 有眼不识泰山
Sorry I've entertained angels unawares
你大人有大量
Please forgive me
小弟上有高堂, 下有弟妹, 求你放我一马!
I have parents. brother and sister
好人有好报, 不报有人报
A good person has a good return
爸爸, 那个人还在跟着我们
Daddy. he's still hollowing us
让他跟踪, 不要吓怕他, 装作不知道
Never mind. pretend not to notice anything
刚才你为什么揭穿他？还打了他一顿
Why did you expose him and beat him up?
我们目的是要让陈查礼知道我们在那里
Our aim is to let Charlie know where we are
太容易得到的消息他不会珍惜的
He won't treasure anything easy to get
有道理
It makes sense
干杯…
Cheers
我请, 不用客气
I'll be the host Help yourselves
我要喝酒, 酒是我的人生
I want to drink Wine is my life
如果没有酒, 就等于世界末日
It's the end of the world without wine
我们来听歌
Let's listen to the music
琴师, 不要睡觉!
Piano player. don't sleep
起来, 琴师
Get up. piano player
弹琴给我们听, 我们要听歌
Play some music for us
是这样的, 看惯了
Well I'm used to it
陈先生
Mr Chan
有马云龙的消息？
Any news of Ma Yun-lung?
我们到处找过了,连户口部和巡捕房也查过了
We've checked even the Census and the police
也没有马云龙的踪迹
but found no trace of him
陈先生, 要不要跟踪他？
Mr Chan. shall we follow him?
不用, 你先回去吧!
No you go back first
我不听…
I'm in no mood for this music
这种音乐好像哭丧似的, 去殡仪馆听好了
It sounds like a dirge
我来是寻开心, 我不喜欢这种音乐
I'm here for pleasure. not for this
是这样的, 看惯了
Well, I'm used to it
陈大哥
Brother Chan
为什么弄成这个样子？
Why have you got this?
都是怪自己跟踪技术差, 被卓非凡打了一顿
I was beaten up by Cho Fei-fan
for following him
是意料中事
That's expected
幸好这次没有白白受打, 终于被我跟踪到好料!
Luckily I got some tips out of it
什么好料？
What tips?
先叫点饮料, 九叔, 老子好了
Order some drink first As usual
跌打p酒啊？
Tien Chi Bone-setting wine?
威士忌啊!
Whisky
你知不知道卓非凡去找谁？
You know who Cho Fei-fan is looking for?
不知道
No
贾亦真
Chia Yi-chen
这个就是他的地址
Here's his address
你知不知道贾亦真是谁？
Do you know the background of Chia?
贾亦真是谁, 我早就知道
Of course I do
我查了一整天的事, 你早就知道？
You do? I've checked the whole day
贾亦真和朱义盛, 合称伪林双杰,专造假金
Chia and Chu are both counterfeit expert?
伪林双杰？
Counterfeit?
朱义盛专造假金
Chu Yi-sheng is said to
specialize in gold fakes
贾亦真除了假金之外, 什么都敢做
Chia specializes in anything besides gold
什么都敢做？
Anything?
是, 包括假的处女膜
Yes, including the making of hymens?
去年造了两个, 到现在还没有人发现
The two he made last year
are still undetected
处女膜也有假的？
Even hymens can be man-made?
这种东西有多少人能分辨呢
Who can ever identify it?
第一次不是心急就是慌慌张张的
The first time is either nervous or impatient
是这样的, 看惯了, 喝一杯就醉
He's used to get drunk easily
司机, 花旗饭店
Driver. the American Hotel
你不要吐呀
Don't vomit
你放心, 我不会呕吐在你的车里
Don't worry. I won't vomit here
小心点!
Careful
是不是？我说过不会呕吐在你的车里
I told you I wouldn't vomit in your oar
我到了
Here I am
我给你车钱
The fare
这么多年不见, 我很挂念你
I missed you all these years
李察, 你记得这首歌吗？
Richard. remember this song?
你最喜欢听的
It was your favorite song
李察…
Richard, Richard...
你看我的婚纱漂不漂亮？
Is my bridal dress beautiful?
我们可以去教堂了
Let's go to the Church
我们去吧
Let's go
下雨？
Is it raining?
你是谁？
Who are you?
你喝醉了, 是我送你回来的,我叫陈查礼
You were drunk I escorted you back
I'm Charlie
我们现在做什么好呀？
What shall We do now?
干了
It's dry
让我来, 你先去换衣服
Let me Go and change
有什么可以帮你？
Can I help you?
查礼
Charlie
老狐狸找过你？
Old Fox has met you before?
查礼, 你听我说
Charlie, listen
你知道我的原则, 我是不会说顾客的秘密
I have my principles to keep
confidential for my clients
我知道!
I Know
老狐狸叫你造假的可兰经
Old Fox told you to make a fake Koran
不要逼我了, 我已说过…
Don't press me. I've already said
不用说了, 你的眼睛已经告诉我
Okay your eyes have betrayed you
替我照做老狐狸需要的东西
Make the same thing Old Fox needs for me
查礼
Charlie
我也是你的顾客, 我也知道你的原则
I'm your client too
I know your principles
富贵逼人来
Luck's With me now
什么事？
What happened?
又发生什么事？发这么大的脾气干什么呢？
What happened? Why are you flaring up?
爸爸, 他不回来量身, 我怎样替他织啊？
I can't knit without measuring his size
跟我量不是一样吗？
Take my measurements then
你的身材跟他相差这么远
Your figures far from his
爸爸, 陈大哥办完了这件事, 会不会留在这里呢?
Would Chan stay when his missions over?
这要看你的表现了
That'll depend on your performance
进来
Come in
吴老板, 有人找陈先生
Boss Ng. a visitor of Mr Chan
找陈先生? 叫他进来..., 是
Show him in
请进去
Please come in
这位小姐找陈先生有什么事吗？
Why are you looking for Mr Chan. Miss?
请问查礼在不在？
Is Charlie in, please?
我的陈大哥出去了
My brother Chan is out
是吗？
Is that so?
有什么需要我转告的？
Any message?
他昨晚留下了一些东西在我这里, 我特地来还给他
I'm bringing back something
he left with me last nignt
可不可以让我转交给他呢？
Can I give it to him for you?
谢谢你!
Thank you
慢走!
Goodbye
请你对他说, 我跟他做的事,我不会对其他人说的
Tell him I'll keep everything confidential
让我看看是什么？
Let me see what It us
人家的东西不要拿来乱看
Keep your nose away from these
下流!
Dirty
干爹 、 月影
Godfather, Yueh Ying
回来了吗？昨晚遗失的东西, 有人送回来给你!
Back? Someone's returning the thing
you left behind last night
谁送东西给我？
Who?
就是你的女朋友
Your girlfriend
我的女朋友？
My girlfriend?
以后出去玩千万得不要G三落四!
Next Mme be more careful
是的, 我认为安全方面我要考虑清楚
Right, we should improve our security
一定, 一定要安全
Sure sure
我是说展览馆的安全呀!
I mean the security of the Exhibition Hall
内部装修?
Interior decoration?
干什么呢？
What does it mean?
保安设施已经改装好了
The security installation has been remodeled
叫所有兄弟进来!.....是
Tell all fellows to come in
陈大哥, 兄弟们都到齐了
Chan everybodys here
各位, 我们这次改装, 主要加强保安系统
The idea of this is to strengthen security
在大门内加了三道铁闸
3 more iron gates will be
installed at tne entrance
小明, 你过来!.....是
Ming. come here
你按一按白色的o!
Press the button
新发明呀!
A new invention
陈大哥, 怎样才可以把它上升起来？
How can we hoist it. Chan?
我有钥匙
I have the Key
每天展览完毕之后,你负责按o把它锁上
Lock it everyday after the exhibition
翌日我会把它打开的
I'll open it the following day
是
Yes
为了谨慎起见, 我们再检查一次!...是…
For safety's sake, let's check once more
假人？
A dummy?
大家不用怕, 紧守岗位
Don't be afraid. Stick to your posts
来不及了, 快点走吧!
Too late Let's go away
陈大哥, 爸爸出了事…
Chan. daddy's in trouble
后面有支枪指着我呀
A gun's pointed at me from behind
陈大哥, 当心我爸爸
Chan be care about my daddy
老狐狸, 你一向用脑不用枪
Old Fox, you never use guns
这次不是你的风格, 太低招了
You're now disgracing yourself
查礼, 高手当前, 没办法呀!
Charlie, I have no choice
in front of a strong rival
低招胜无招, 对不对？
A dirty gimmick is better than none, right?
好, 你想怎么样？
Well, what do you want?
当然是想要那本真的发绣可兰经
That genuine Koran of course
我已说过那本经书在展览馆被人偷去
I told you already it was stolen
听到了吧
Hear that?
展览馆的是贾亦真造的假经书
That one was a Chia fake
那本真的应该在你身上
The genuine one should be with you
放下你的枪
Drop It
不然吴老先生身体立刻会穿个洞
or Mr Ng will be bullet-ridden
是的, 后面还有个小女孩呀!
Right, there's still a girl behind you
不是, 是一个拿着枪的少女
No, an armed girl
你交出真经我就立刻把吴老先生放走
Give me that real Koran. and I'll let him go
我不知道你说些什么?
What are you talking about?
那本真经书是不是在你这里呀？
Is that genuine Koran with you
展览馆那本是假的？
That one at the Hall is a counterfeit?
如果那本真经书在你这里, 你就…
If the real one is with you...
千万不要交出来
don't ever hand it over
你…
You
你杀我, 你杀了我吧
Kill me, kill me !
爸爸, 她没有枪的
Daddy she's not armed
爸爸
Daddy
乖女儿
Darling
老狐狸, 真棒
Old Fox, you are very clever
果然没破你的金漆招牌, 用脑不用枪
So you've stuck to your golden
rule, use brain but not gun
没办法了, 遇到一条烂命, 算我倒霉!
No way, I'm helpless against a desperado
女儿, 我们走
Daughter, let's go
查理, 这移花接木, 监守自盗的桥段
Charlie, only Mr Ng could have been
吴老先生会被你骗倒
trapped by your trick
不过你骗不到我
You can't outwit me
立刻把那本真经书拿出来
Give me that real Koran
你相信这个老狐狸
You trust that Old Fox
任何人我也不相信, 我只信我自己
I trust nobody but myself
你以为我会监守自盗吗？
You think I'll steal things
不是以为, 简直是
I'm sure you will
爸爸, 陈大哥不会这样做的
Daddy, brother Chan Won't do that
住口!
Shut up!
上次改装保安统, 我已经怀疑了
I've suspected that remodeled
security system already
那次…
That time
不用多说了, 你的保安工作到此为止
Enough, Your mission's over
如果还不交出来, 我就一枪把你干掉
Hand it over or I'Il shoot you down
好
Okay
陈大哥…
Brother Chan, brother Chan
别管他, 让他去
Don't mind him, let him go
查礼, 人情冷暖呀!
Charlie, men are fickle
好吧! 胜败兵家常事
Win or loss is common
想不到你这样绝, 用离间计
I've never thought of your sowing
discord between us?
你应该感谢我才是呀!
You should thank me
不然怎么看见吴老头的真面目呢?
Otherwise, you wouldn't
have seen his true face
来喝杯吧!.....好!
Come and have a drink
你已经不负责保安了, 还跟着我干什么？
Why follow me? you're no Manger on duty
世事很难预料的
Everything is hard to tell
就像喝酒一样,没喝到最后一杯也不知道谁会醉
You can't tell who's drunk till the last cup
对, 我们喝个明白
Right, let's drink and see
放在哪里才安全呢?
Where to place it?
行了, 放在椅子下就安全了!
Tuck it under the chair
还是不行, 这年头谁都靠不住, 连干儿子都出卖我!
You can't trust anyone these days
万一女儿也帮他那就糟了, 不行!
If my daugther helps him,
it will be trouble. No
行了, 是了, 放在这里!
Good, It is 0k as it is here
不行, 经书还是不能放在家里
This one can't put at home, No
别动!
Don't move
原来是你, 你来干什么？
So it's you! Why are you here?
对不起, 吴老先生
Sorry, Mr Ng
查礼在不在？我要找他
Is Charlie in? I must see him
他不在, 以后也不会回来
No, and he'll never be here
哪里可以找到他呢？我很想见他
Where can I find him? I want to see him
这种人不见也罢了
Is he worthy of your care?
今晚我要乘夜车离开这里
I must get out of here by express tonight
我想见他最后一面, 顺便把东西还给他
I want to see him for the last
time and return him this
这些东西丢掉吧
Throw it away
把它丢掉？不行
Throw It away? No
他在展览馆装修那天交给我保管
He put this in my custody
when the hall was decorated
我想一定是很重要的
It must be important
他还说, 如果找不到他, 就把它丢掉
He even told me to destroy it
if I failed to find him
我不知该怎么办
I don't know what to do
当然, 不要丢掉
Don't throw it away
怎样交给他呢？
How can I hand it over to him?
交给我吧!
Give it to me
还是不好,他交给我保管就是不想让其他人知道!
Oh, no. he wouldn't let others know it
如果我交给你, 就是失信于他
I'll betray him if I handed it to you
虽然他不理我
Though he doesn't care for me
但是我也不希望我们分开以后, 留下一个坏印象
I wouldn't leave a bad impression
我还是要去找他
I must find him by every means
如果真的找不到他, 我才把它丢掉
I'll destroy this if I fail
好吧, 丢远一点更好
Throw It away the farmer the better
（ 在这变幻的市镇, 半粒花生也可当真金 ）
In this mirage of a town,
peanuts become gold
（ 碰埋就有老衬, 会信我信到晕 ）
fools will trust me to a fault
（ 但我判别光与暗, 看得清楚永不会失真 ）
I alone can tell light from darkness
（ 去明辨对与错, 有智勇有信心 ）
Right from wrong I'm wise and brave
（ 世事如棋根本是贪过瘾 ）
Yes, the world is a stage
（ 让潮流循环如三脚凳 ）
Events go round like music chairs
（ 间中假会变真 ）
Sometime a lie becomes the truth
（ 会变假, 会变真, 到真假不分 ）
Now a lie, now the truth. The mind boggles
（ 正义长存心中像一个印 ）
But justice is embossed in every heart
（ 让豪情源源由心里渗 ）
Wherefrom oozes boisterans feelings
（ 靠我真意真心 ）
With my true heart
（ 看清假, 看清真, 看得真 ）
I see through falsehoods and true Words
（ 真真假假真 ）
True, true, false, false, true
（ 假假真真真 ）
False, false, true, true, true
（ 真真假假 ）
True, true, false, false
（ 假假真真 ）
False, false, true, true
（ 真真假假真真 ）
True, true, false, false, true, true
（ 假假真真真 ）
False, false, true, true, true
（ 真真假假真 ）
True, true, false, false, true
（ 真真假假 ）
True, true, false, false
（ 假假真真 ）
False, false, true, true
（ 真真真真真 ）
True, True, True, True, True
（ 假变真 ）
Then falsehood becomes truth
真痛快, 下次再玩!.....好!
It's kicks Let's play again next time
卓老, 你似乎胜券在握
Cho, you seem sure of success
你还年轻, 有的是时间, 输得起!
You're young and you've got time
我提醒你, 有赌未必输定
Listen. there's no loss
till the result's known
我也提醒你, 学人家盖前浪
Let me remind you not to overcome the oldest
小心水性不精, 很容易反被盖过来
Or you may easily be overcome
without experience
真真假假真, 假假真真真, 真真假假
True is false, false is true
开车
Go
是她？
It's her'?
陈大哥
Brother Chan
小明, 跟着前面的车
Ming. follow that car in front
我回吴家看看, 知道他们在哪里立刻通知我!
I'm back to Ng's now Notify me
when you know where they are
小心点呀!
Be alert
干爹, 我交给你的经书在不在？
Have you got the scroll I gave you?
那本假经书我还给你的女朋友了
I returned that fake one to your girlfriend
顺便换回真的!
and exchanged it for the real one
你…你不要乱来呀!
You...  No monkey business'
人算不如天算, 想不到会自动送上门
Things go beyond predictions
我辛辛苦苦安排那本假的来骗马云龙
I tried hard to cheat Ma with a false
你有胆子用命保护那本经书
You protected it with your life
为何这么糊涂相信那女子, 被人骗了呀!
Why did you get cheated by that girl?
我不相信!
I don't believe it
那本真的已经在老狐狸那里
Old Fox has got that real one
不相信？你验验它
Check it if you don't believe
贾亦真
Chia Yi-chen
相信别人, 现在相信我也没用了
Trust others Now it's useless
even to trust me
别乱来......你让我死去吧!
Don't be foolish Let me die
你大不了失掉保险公司
At worst you lose your insurance company
如果你死了, 你叫月影以后怎么办？
If you died, how about your daughter?
小明, 怎么样？
Hsiao Ming. what now?
希望我能及时把经书抢回来
Hope that I can get back the Koran in time
卓老!
Cho
现在你可名正言顺接收吴氏保险公司
How you can take over Ng's insurance Clo
真不愧为老江湖, 值得…
You're unreservedly an experienced had
看看够不够数
Count it if it's enough
连我也不相信
You don't trust me?
不是不相信你, 是不相信全世界任何人
Not you only. but the whole world
高见…
Fantastic
喝杯酒庆祝一下吧!
Let's drink for a celebration
值得!
It's worthwhile
无论如何先喝一口法国干邑白兰地
A shot of cognac, come what may
卓老, 赶时间吗？
Cho, are you in a hurry?
做人赶时间, 总比时间赶人好呀!
It's better to hurry when the hurrying's good
卓老的意思是赶时间总比被时间赶好!
He means it's better to hurry
than being hurried
都是被时间赶的人
You're all hurried by time
爸爸, 数目对了
Daddy, the amount is right
我们走吧!
Let's go
时间刚好!
It's just the right time
卓老, 等一等
Cho, wait
卓老, 不知这粒玻璃可否当印度之星呢?
Cho, could this grain become Indian Star?
在我手上就可以
Yes, only if it's in my hand
大家商量一下吧 ， 看看有什么桥段
Let's meet and see if there's any gimmick
考虑一下吧 ， 卓老
Think it over, Cho
老板…
Boss, Boss
快点扶起他
Help him at once
太贪心很容易会摔死的
Greed could trap you to death
你怎么样, 没事吧？
Are alright?
没事…
Fine, fine
卓老, 不送你了!
Cho, I Won't see you out
老板, 是不是要车？
Boss, want a rickshaw?
去哪里？
Where to?
去大酒店
The Hong Kong Hotel
把可兰经还给我, 不然对你不客气
Give me the Koran, or I'll be nasty
你有对我客气过吗？
Have ever been nice to me?
对不起!
Sorry
姐姐, 接着
Sister, catch it
想追？
Want to follow her?
好了, 现在一拍两散, 便宜了卓非凡
Now Cho's reaped the benefit
什么也没有了
Now we've got nothing
我不要紧, 倾家荡产的不是我
I needn't worry, it's not me going bust
你就惨了!
But I feel pity for you
女人嘛! 到处都是
Girls can be easily got everywhere
说得对, 我要回上海了
Good, I'll go back to Shanghai
好, 我也去北京
I'll go back to Peking
希望下次不要再见了, 请!
Hope we won't meet again
先生, 你的行李
Your luggage, sir
谢谢!
Thank you
我知道了, 当然…
I Know. Of course
西瓜刨是吗？你不是说了, 说话总是不清楚
Watermelon? Forget it. you never talk clearly
不要吵, 你又不是西瓜刨!   你…
Quiet' You 're not Watermelon
爸爸, 经书弄妥了
Daddy I've got the Koran
为什么会这样子？你没事吧？
Why? Are you alright?
姐姐差点没命,没想到陈查礼竟然会救她
Sister nearly got killed,
but Charlie saved her
还不帮爸爸搬行李？我们要尽快离开这里
Help daddy with the luggage
We must get out of here now
何必这么急, 你怕他们会追踪过来吗？
No hurry, they won't trace you up here
我们走吧, 免得夜长梦多
Let's go to avoid unnecessary troubles
还想着他？不是想把爸爸出卖吧？
Still thinking of him? Want to betray daddy?
走吧!
Let's go
别动!
Don't move
卓老, 想不到这个时候你还笑得出来
Cho, never thought you could still smile now
想不到是你先到一步
So you've stolen a march
有好东西我不会缺席的
I won't lose in getting precious things
我们三个终于又碰头了
We three met again at last
卓老 ， 你不像是替宋金荣工作的人
Cho, you don't look like one working for Sung
你也是为了经书
You're aimed at the Koran too
把经书拿出来
Take out the Koran
我有个坏习惯, 得不到的东西我很想得到
I enjoy fetching things I can't get
得到的东西我不会放掉的
I never lose What I've got
陈大哥, 你来了我就放心
Brother Chan, I'm now at ease
我也有个坏习惯, 答应了朋友一定做到底
I always help a friend to the last
看来我们三个没人肯放手
It seems none of us will give up
就算我肯放手, 那本经书两位谁要？
Even if I do. which of you will get it?
这N说, 我们三个人之中, 有两个一定要躺下来咯
So two of us must fall
我们来一次公平的决斗
Let's have a fair fight
每次只准用一粒子弹好吗？
Each of us must use one bullet only, OK?
两位预备枪吧!
Get your guns gentlemen
陈大哥, 我有
Brother Chan, I've got one
你小心一点
Watch out!
放心, 我一定可以取回经书的
Don't worry, we'll get back the Koran
你的枪呢？
Your gun?
两位也知道我从来不用枪的
You Know I never use guns
一把刀等于一粒子弹
One knife means one bullet
现在要看哪个有本领
Now see which one of us can kill
能够在这么短时间内, 做到一石二鸟, 一箭双雕
two birds with one stone in a twinkle
一
二
三
爸爸…
Daddy, daddy
你们竟然先对付刀子？
So you coped with the one with knife first
别动, 我们愿赌服输, 是要讲信用的
Don't move. We're reconciled to defeat
老狐狸, 不要装死了, 起来吧!
Old Fox, get up, don't cheat
想我们两败俱伤, 然后坐收渔人之利
You're trying to reap the fisherman's luck
想得真周到
You're crafty
好
Okay
现在是我和他们两位的事
Now It's between me and them
无论发生什么事, 不准插手
Come what may, don't interfere
本来我想节省一点力
I wanted to save some energy
既然两位坚持三个人之中要倒下两人
You insist on having two of us fall
即是逼我出手
So I have no choice
谁先上？
Who'll come fist
我从不欺负老人家的, 你放弃吧!
I never bully an old man. Give up
手脚是很快, 不过没有力
Nimble, but not strong enough
他说你不怎么样, 我就不相信了
I don't believe that
你年纪大, 我让你先歇一歇
You're old, you take a rest
我够了, 你请便
Enough. You, please
倒下来
Fallen
对, 说得对, 只是快, 没有力
Right, Fast, but without strength
轮到两位了
The turn of you two
干什么？
What are you doing?
什么？
What?
我是说轮到你们两个对打呀!
It's your turn to fight against each other
太狠了, 真的想我摔倒下来？
How cruel You want me to fall?
幸好这沙发不是我的
Luckily this sofa is not mine
快点下来
Get down quickly
你说下来就下来那我岂不是很听话幔
You expect me to be so obedient?
小子, 快点放手
Sonny, let go
好位置, 不要放手
Good position, don't let go
放手呀!
Let go
小心呀!
Watch out
痛了吧!
It hurts
不打了？
Giving up.
不知道谁痛呢？
Who's suffering?
是他…
He
散了
Finished
不知道谁痛呢？
Who's suffering?
压扁了!
Flattened
爸爸说过不要插手的
Daddy promised not to intervene
不要…
Don't,don't
你们不要放手
Don't let go
老狐狸, 认输了吗？
Old Fox, reconciled to defeat?
千万不要放手
Don't ever let go
还不把经书拿出来, 我就推你下去
The Koran, or I'll push you down
我有畏高症的, 我输了…
I have acrophobia
爸爸…
Daddy
把经书还给他们
Give them the Koran
爸爸, 我们这么辛苦才得到经书, 真的要给他们？
Daddy are you sure after
we fought so hard for it?
我说过愿赌服输的, 快点!
I promised to be reconciled
to defeat. Come on
爸爸
Daddy
快点!
Hurry up
不送你了
I won't see you out
三个之中最先摔下来的是我
I'm the first to fall
不知道最后会剩下哪一个
Which's going to be the last
我们走
Let's go
你们不要打了
Don't fight
这本经书是假的
This Koran is a fake
假的？
A fake?
姐姐, 快点, 火车快要开了
Sister, hurry up, the train's leaving
我很担心陈查礼他…
I'm worried that Charlie Chan...
不要乱讲!
Don't go into wild thinking
不是呀, 我是担心他们会追过来
I'm worried he might follow up
放心, 我从不会算错的
Don't worry, I never go wrong
他们来到的时候, 我们早已经走了
By the time they come we'd have left
爸, 那本经书对你是否真的这么重要？
Daddy, is the Koran so important to you?
游戏最有趣的地方就是玩的过程
The fun of a game is the process of playing
现在胜负已定, 那经书还有什么价值呢?
When the game's over, the value's gone
那我放心了!
I'll feel at ease then
真甜
It's very sweet
你现在开始玩一个更危险的游戏
You are playing a dangerous game
陈先生？
Mr Chan?
陈查礼先生？
Charlie Chan?
有位很漂亮的小姐吩咐我交给你
A pretty girl wants me to give you this
如果我是你, 一定不会让她走的
If I were you, I'd let her go
（ 在这变幻的市镇, 半粒花生也可当真金 ）
In this mirage of a town, peanuts become gold
（ 碰埋就有老衬, 会信我信到晕 ）
Fools will trust me to a fault
（ 但我判别光与暗, 看得清楚永不会失真 ）
I alone can tell light from darkness
（ 去明辨对与错, 有智勇有信心 ）
Right from wrong. I'm wise and brave
（ 世事如棋根本是贪过瘾 ）
Yes, the world is a stage
（ 让潮流循环如三脚凳 ）
Events go round like music chairs
（ 间中假会变真 ）
Sometime a lie becomes the truth
（ 会变假, 会变真, 到真假不分 ）
Now a lie, now the truth The mind boggles
（ 正义长存心中像一个印 ）
But justice is embossed in every heart
（ 让豪情源源由心里渗 ）
Wherefrom oozes boisterans feelings
（ 靠我真意真心 ）
With my true heart
（ 看清假, 看清真, 看得真 ）
I see through falsehoods and true Words
（ 真真假假真 ）
True. true. false. false. true
（ 假假真真真 ）
False. false. true. true. true
（ 真真假假 ）
True. true. false. false
（ 假假真真 ）
False. false. true. true
（ 真真假假真真 ）
True. true. false. false. true. true
（ 假假真真真 ）
False. false. true. true. true
（ 真真假假真 ）
True. true. false. false. true
（ 真真假假 ）
True. true. false. false
（ 假假真真 ）
False. false. true. true
（ 真真真真真 ）
True.True.True.True.True
（ 假变真 ）
Then falsehood becomes truth